and we are live so
welcome everyone to
the 6300 software
development process
my name is shin and with
me is the instructor paula
and today we have justin
and we should have will as
well but i i think he's
joining shortly so paula and
justin will please say hi
and then I will go through
the ritual with the schedule
and some announcements.
Hi, everybody. Welcome
to this office hour.
And Shin, I saw Will
appearing, but also
disappeared. So maybe
now he's in page two.
Anyway.
Oh, yeah, I see Will here, but
he... Okay, and
then I see that he's
unmuted, but I don't
see his video yet.
I'll go while you're waiting
on him. Hi, everyone. I'm
Justin. You may recognize
me from Ed Discussions. I
look forward to this semester
and this office hours.
Cool. So while we
are waiting for you,
so this week we are,
students, okay, here
we go. Well, my wife
is also having a
meeting with her siblings
behind me, so you'll
probably hear that
as well. I apologize.
But hi, everyone.
Actually, I think the sound
quality from me is really good.
Anyway, I was saying
that this week is what as
opposed to what's a
lecture, object-oriented
engineering and UML, P2L2.
and v2l3 android development
that android development
is also related to the
current assignment
assignment for simple android
app why the the previous
lecture object-oriented
engineering it will be
it will be relevant once
we go to group project
or actually assignment
and five as well, assignment
five input project.
And some of you
may have known that
we have a certain
problem with CrayScope
AutoPrayer for
the last two days.
Thankfully, and thanks
to Justin, we finally get
it resolved. So everything
should be working
properly right now. That
being said, the instructional
staff is still
monitoring the situation.
All right.
Anything from our
team, from Paola,
before we get started
with the questions?
This has been a crazy
week for me. Everything is
piling up. I'm just looking
forward to next Tuesday.
What happened next Tuesday?
So the things that are piling
up is that I'm organizing
in my college Innovation
Quest, to this big event
that is on saturday and
then the day after so next
week i'll see you from
there i'm going to a
conference and next tuesday
i have to give a one hour
presentation now this is
not a good thing to say in
front of the students but
it's one hour presentation
and for now on wednesday
february 4th so less than a
week from the presentation
i have two slides so i
mean i didn't procrastinate
i just didn't have the
time it's everything here
i just need to put it down
well um i think it's uh
something related to uh to the
professor the instructor
from the uh um the other
class that i was in um it's
not about the um the last
minute it's about knowing
when the last minute it is.
I think it's Thursday
night so if by tomorrow I
don't have half of the
slides I will start panicking
but let's see I mean the
flight is not long enough
to say you know like I'm gonna
make it work there so but
I'm keeping it together
for now but this is the
presentation we voted on
last week so I decided to go
with the formal requirements
part so if anybody was
curious okay so let's get
started with our official
question so first question
is hi quick question
about krayscope versus
intellij results all of my
tests passed locally in
intellij with several hidden
krayscope tests failed
even when krayscope show an
expected output that
appeared identical to the
original string And I noticed
that when I adjusted my
code to match trace code
expected output, my score
improved, but it broke
the actual logic, meaning
transformation no longer
occur when they should have.
Because of this, I don't
change my logic. So my
question is, do we do what's
best for assignment or
do we have to slowly go
off autoplayer's response?
I wanted to make sure I
was switching the root
cause rather than just
matching the output.
Thanks.
For this,
Will, you want to take a shot?
I can go if he doesn't.
Yeah,
Justin sounds like
he's more prepared
than I am, so
let's go with that.
Yeah, Justin. Sorry
to cut you off, unless
you want to, but
chime in after me. So
I saw this that got
posted a while ago.
So something that should
be understood about the
instructor tests is that we
purposely are not showing
you what we're inputting
and expecting to be output,
right? Well, we show a
little bit in the Gradescope,
but you're not going to be
able to see what you see
in Gradescope on the instructor
side and reproduce it
locally because you don't
have the parameters that
we provide to the tests.
And that's by design, right?
So this is frustrating to
a lot of students because,
right, we don't give
you the instruction, the
instructor test suite but
if we did that understand
that the assignment would
be extremely trivial
right if you knew exactly
what the tests were going
to be so um the comment
about trying to reproduce
it locally i just want
to say that you you can't
necessarily do that
unfortunately so um but what you
can do is see if there's
patterns or different
things that you're seeing
in the grade scope output
that might indicate an
issue locally and you can
write your own test i think
this was about a three
and that's one of the first
ones that you're actually
interacting with the
autograder the way that that we
usually do later on in the
semester so it's a little bit
of a learning curve but
speaking from experience
sometimes in the production
environment you don't have you
don't have the inputs right
you just have a stack tracer
some sort of error message
that's vague so you got
to go with what you have
and so that's sort of the
lesson there I wanted to throw
out there we only want to
kind of what i would throw in
as well by the way somebody's
got their hand up uh add
your question in in um
on um piazza um we don't
actually take them here but um
yeah i i would kind of
agree if uh you shouldn't be
changing your code to match
the expected output but if
the expect if if grade scope
is telling you that the
result you're getting is not
matching correctly. It means
something you've done doesn't
really work correctly.
So you shouldn't be changing
it to match the output.
You should be changing
it to figure out why your
code isn't doing what
we're expecting it to do.
I can't give you any more
specifics than that, but
you shouldn't code to
the output. But if the
output is saying something
different, then you probably
are not doing something
the way you should be.
I'm not sure what
else to say besides
that, but that sounds
like good advice.
So to add to that,
please do not. So for
this assignment and later
assignment as well,
when we have the test,
sometimes Sometimes we
show the expected output
and the actual output
from students program.
However, we do
not show the test
input, the instructor
test input.
And that's again,
that's by design
as Justin and
Will already said.
Please do not circumvent that.
students are actually there
there are way to circumvent
but we do check for that
and it and if we discover
that we will deduct points
from some students so
that's one thing I want
to say and the other thing
is this is actually we
already do it a little bit
more relaxed than what you
would see let's say on this
code so on this code i
think you don't even see
your um the the output as
well and then think about it
in the industry right um
you may not have the oracle
who knows everything and
who who knows uh to write
on the test you have to
figure it by yourself or
your The team has to figure
it by themselves, right?
So even now you are
struggling with the correct
logic of the code just
to match the Oracle here.
You will have even more
problems when working in
the industry writing software
with the correctness.
So I know it's frustrating,
but at least you are now
in the learning environment,
and it doesn't fail.
Okay, so if the team
doesn't have any more,
then we can move on
to the next question.
Speaking about
requirement engineering,
there's an approach
called domain-driven
design. What's your
opinion on this?
Is it practical to use on
real software engineering?
Talking about
requirement engineering,
I think it's Paula's
favorite topic.
Yeah, that's my
favorite subject
today. This is an happy day.
Okay, yes, there is this
method and the overall
idea here is that, so is
it practical to use in
practice? Also, I don't know
how much everybody knows,
but the overall idea here
is that the first step is
to create a language
that is a shared language
between the developers and
the domain expert, right?
And then you start
modeling the domain.
And so the development
starts in a different
way, so starts
centered on the domain.
So one is convenient to use
it. So when the domain is
very complicated, when the
domain is the main source
of complexity in a project,
when the different parts
speak, use the same terms
in different ways. So it's
important to create a common
language. So let me say
something in general. Domain
is always a problem in
requirements, in the requirements
engineering part, right?
Unless it's something extremely
trivial but in some so
there is always this
gap between you and your
stakeholders and they are the
domain expert and you need to
bridge that knowledge but
if a project is you know if
a domain is not extremely
complex and complexity come
from other things this
method is overkilling uh so
now for i'll give you an
example like uh of and then
you can use uh you know every
approach i think this has
been developed in the early
2000 and every approach
you know can be used like
in the pure way as it's been
developed with all you know
applying all the rule in
a very strict way or you
can take things out of it
right so for instance right
um an example is that if you
work in the domain in a
medical domain and you have
your modeling tool that
and but you have a complete
different language with the
people you are talking to
and they have this very
technical jargon that for you
doesn't mean the same thing
when you talk about this i
want to give you a small
example for instance think
about you are developing
some software to support
physiotherapists right and um
you know like you think about
the movement and if you've
never been to physiotherapy
or i don't know let's
let's be very specific
physiotherapy for people that
have spinal injury right like
so you imagine you're
developing games to support
people and now you're thinking
uh you know when you think
about the movement you think
about and i'm sorry i'm
about to say centimeters
because I don't still don't
know how much is an inch
so you might imagining and
so let me just do the Italian
thing let me use my hands
but so you might think
that you know a movement is
something that you can
perceive with your eyes but
sometimes in certain domain
when when they talk about the
movement they are talking
about minimal changes because
it can be very effective
so in this case it's very
important to create a common
jargon. Is it important
to use this approach in
its pure sense? It depends,
because maybe the rest of the
problem is the real problem
and it's not the source
of complexity. But if you
have, I don't know, a very
legally-intricated domain,
a safety-critical domain,
then in that case, if
that's the main source
of complexity, that in
that case, maybe it's
convenient to use it. Now,
my personal opinion, if
anybody is interested,
is that it's also okay to
be flexible and use the
pieces of certain approach
that you need. So by
all means, whatever is
the approach you're using,
keep in mind that the
domain gap between you
and your stakeholders is
a very important problem
when you are trying to
elicit requirements.
i would be if that'd
be me my opinion
um so justin uh justin
uh uh will you have
opinion on this or
more like well said
i don't feel like anything
i could say would improve
on what paula said so
this is my day okay that's
the requirement this is
my thing this is what i
choose today i'm taking i'm
taking it it's just yeah
it's yeah it makes me it
makes me happy so it is
truly your day because
next question is the in the
same topic on requirement
engineering lesson how do
you know when you've
gathered enough requirements
before moving to design would
this depend on realistic
constraints, like time,
resources, stakeholders?
All right, so first of all, I
like the questions
that she say,
enough, because enough is
the right word, right? You
will not, you know, like
you will not ever have
all the requirements. So
this is the first important
thing. So the question is
very well posed. It almost
answers itself uh because
uh when you are listing
requirements uh requirements
continue continuously
evolve right and also you
have different stakeholders
and you can continuously
collect things that then
can start cluttering and
conflicting so enough is
the right word when do i
know that they are enough
constraints definitely play
a role okay so for instance
uh you have uh and and
the constraints including
the one listed in the questions
but also uh for instance
uh the kind of project
you are developing right
there are certain projects in
which i mean then it's still
time but not time in
the sense that you had a
deadline with your with your
person right like if you see
your competitors are coming
up very quickly then being
able to deliver something
quickly it's important
right uh so enough is at some
point so first of all when
your stay you know your
client your main stakeholders
has signed off and they
are okay they the business
owner agree with what you
have done uh you need to
know and this is important
even if of course you don't
know all the requirements but
you need to have understood
well what is in the scope
of your project and what
is not in the scope of your
project right then then
at that point when you
start you need to have
requirements that allow you to
move into design and need to
understand clearly what are
your acceptance criteria
so your requirements need
to be testable in some way
and so now it depends on
it depends on on what you
have right so you have
time constraints you have
a deadline so at some
point you need to decide
okay what at this point you
can say enough requirements
are the core initial
functionality that allow
me to move forward and
deliver something you
might understand that at
some point certain things
are unsolvable that certain
you keep conflicting
and so you need to have
a strategy to prioritize
now you can also go in a in
a so all all the different
you know you might also
have not enough budget to
keep going and so again you
choose for a set of core
functionality then you add
on now depending on the
the development process
you're using it's tricky right
i mean when i was a student
agile was these new things
that people were talking
as like maybe easy thing
but not really uh there
was this idea of you know
some of just iterative this
is what people were saying
i didn't want to sell out
my age but it's i guess you
can find when i graduated
uh and um and so we were
talking about you know
mainly people were doing
waterfall and then you do
waterfall enough is when you can
write a requirement
specification and this is when
an SRS and this is when your
stakeholders sign off right
because your SRS is kind
of your contract this is
what you are promising and
they sign off and that's that's
enough of course you can
have bad requirements
because you might have not
arrived at that point we say
before that your requirements
are actionable that your
requirements define the
scope but but that the SRS is
your contract if If you are
in an agile settings, you
need to find out, okay, what
am I prioritizing? And when
you can move forward with
your first block, you can
keep moving in that
direction. But I love that the
question asked enough,
because requirements are never
finished. So for instance, a
very big issue is our requirement
change, our requirements
evolve, our requirements
are keep added and so keep
track on this evolution
of requirements and how
these reflect to your product
once the product starts
existing in parallel with
your requirements is the
very difficult problem and
also very interesting okay
i can i can talk forever
but i don't know if you want
to listen to me forever.
But yeah, I think
that's probably already
give quite a sufficient
answer to Grace.
But Grace, if you want to
follow up, feel free to.
Then we can continue with
the next unresolved question.
Assignment 4, where can
I get more details on
instruction to set up
development environment?
Also, installing Android
Studio, we install the
dependent things like Gradle,
Ruby, and Ripple Electric.
So as mentioned before,
the Android development,
the lecture is supposed
to be relevant and prepare
you for the assignment.
If you haven't
watched the lecture,
then please do so. If
you already watched the
lecture but still find
it insufficient to
prepare you for the
assignment, please get to us
and um on assignment for
the updated assignment
instructions say to use invalid
input text i think grade
scope is still expecting
invalid message for some of
the tests do the test on
grade scopes you need to be
updated too much the error
message is indicated by the
assignment and as justin
mentioned um nope everything
is fine a lot of students
already get one point i'll
just
if I can add to that
hopefully we can
put some confidence back
into the autograder you know
we were having some issues
with memory but turns out
it wasn't our fault it was
a bug on Gradescope's side
but things are working as
they should please make a
private post if you do have
new issues but the existing
issues that we were having
seem to be resolved so
I think we've gotten most
of the private threads
that people message just
with we ran and they're
and they're working as
expected so have confidence
that things are working
now and if you are seeing
errors test if you're
seeing tests that fail um
try to assume that
it's an issue with
your code not not the
auto grader but please
please reach out
if you're concerned
that's it
okay so if no other then we
can code it today or tonight
all right then uh thank
you uh thank you all
and yeah i will let
others say goodbye as well
bye everybody bye so long
everyone did i interrupt you